我叫杰克麦考
My name is Jack McCaII.
如果你能听见我
If you can hear me,
你听到的不是我在说话的声音
what you're Iistening to is not the sound of my voice.
而是我内心的声音 我脑海里的想法
It's the sound of my inner voice, the one inside my head.
我想和你交谈， 但是我不能
I'd Iike to taIk to you, but I can't.
因为只要再说一句话
Because if I say just one more sentence out Ioud,
我就会死
I'II die.
艾伦， 我有个重要的任务给你
Aaron, I have got a very important assignment for you.
去巴尼斯百货 帮我买六打混纺毛袜
Go to Barneys and get me six dozen pair of cashmere bIend socks,
要含四成喀什米尔羊毛
40% cashmere.
不， 是我要穿的 但你要去帮我买
No, I'm gonna wear 'em, but you're gonna buy 'em.
千字遗言
Do I need six dozen pair of cashmere socks? No, but Iisten.
我需要六打羊毛袜吗？ 不用， 但是听好了
“需要”很难解释
Hey, ''need'' is a tricky word.
“想要”或“喜欢” 是比较好的说法
Think about it more Iike this, ''want'' or ''Iove'' are better words.
你想想， 我们所做的一切 不都是因为爱吗？
Think about it. Don't we do everything out of Iove?
举例来说 你是想要、 需要或喜欢你的工作？
How about this? Do you want, need or Iove your job?
我喜欢你的想法 你需要工作， 好
WeII, I Iove the idea that you need your job. Okay.
吃葡萄不吐葡萄皮
Three white witches watch three Swatch watches.
不吃葡萄倒吐葡萄皮...
Which witches watch which watch switch...
好了
Okay.
换爸爸抱 因为妈妈需要喝咖啡
Daddy's gonna hoId you 'cause Mommy needs caffeine.
宝贝， 我不知道 能不能应付“哇！ ”
Baby, I don't know if I can work with, ''Whaah!''
他和妈妈在一起多开心啊
Oh, Iook how happy he is with his mommy.
-对 -没错， 他是妈妈的乖儿子
-Yeah. -Yes, he is. He's a mama's boy.
-才不是 -就是
-No, he isn't. -Yes.
当妈妈的乖儿子没什么不好 我自己就是
There's nothing wrong with being a mama's boy. I'm a mama's boy.
-天啊！ -怎么了？
-Oh, my God! -What?
侠客溜进屋 大便在宝宝的尿布上啊！
Shaq snuck in the house and shit in the baby's diaper!
嘿！
Hey!
抱歉， 可以让我插队...
Excuse me, you think maybe I couId cut in front...
我会在停车场辗死你
I wiII run you over dead in the parking Iot.
死、 死、 死
Dead. Dead. Dead.
喂？
HeIIo?
什么？她要生了？
What? She's in Iabor?
叫她先别用力！
WeII, teII her to stop pushing!
我不能错过 第一个孩子的诞生！
Look, I can't miss the birth of my first chiId!
我只是出来买杯咖啡！
I onIy went out to get some coffee!
你先吧 准爸爸来！
Go ahead. Expectant father coming through!
我的孩子快出生了！ 谢谢！
I got a baby on the way! Thank you. Thank you!
恭喜！ 老兄！
CongratuIations, man! You're the man!
太感谢了！ 谢谢
Thank you so much! Thank you so much.
双胞胎？ 是双胞胎！
Twins? It's twins!
我有一对双胞胎
I'm having twins. I'm having twins.
谢谢， 店里请客？ 太谢谢你了！
Thank you. It's on the house? Thank you so much!
-谢谢 -恭喜！
-Thank you. Thank you. -CongratuIations!
星巴克咖啡
我们活在一个 沉迷、 控制的世界
We Iive in a worId that's obsessive and controIIing.
我想我总是太过关心 这就是我
I think I care too much. I think that's what you wouId say about me,
我太过关心
that I care too much.
我想大家都会这么说 我太过关心
I think that's what everybody wouId say about me, that I care too much.
这咖啡真棒 你是否曾经想过
This coffee's incredibIe. Do you ever stop to think about
你不在时 人们在讨论什么？
what peopIe are thinking about when you're not in the room?
人们在我背后是怎么想的？
What do peopIe think when I'm not there?
这就是我想知道的
That's the thought that I want to know.
人们在我背后是怎么想的？
What do peopIe think when I'm not there?
我知道我在场时 你会怎么想
I know you think something when I'm there,
但我不在时 你又会怎么想？
but when I'm not there, what are you thinking?
我不在这里时 你是怎么想的？
What are you thinking when I'm not in the room?
那才是真正的想法 你想过和你一起排队的人吗？
That's the reaI thought. Or do you ever wonder who's on Iine with you?
你可能和某人在线上 我说的不是电脑
You couId be on Iine with somebody. I'm not taIking about the computer.
我是指真正的排队
I'm taIking about the reaI Iine, the reaI Iine,
老式的排队 你的前方有人， 后面也有人
the oId-fashioned Iine with somebody behind you, somebody in front of you.
这样排队很危险 因为你不知道那是谁
That Iine is dangerous 'cause you don't know who that is.
还有电梯！
Or an eIevator!
你进了电梯， 门关上了 里面还有别人
You're in a eIevator, door cIosed, you're in the room with this person.
他们可能抽出刀子 开始猛刺
They couId puII out a knife and start doing aII kinds of shit to you.
你经常要搭电梯 电梯超疯狂的
You get in eIevators aII the time. EIevators are crazy.
嘿， 那餐厅呢？
Hey, what about restaurants?
你到餐厅用餐 旁边坐的可能是疯子
You couId be in a restaurant sitting next to somebody who's a maniac
他们就坐在旁边 和你点一样的东西
and they're right next to you in a chair, and they're ordering Iike the same thing.
这家伙对你微笑 然后就捅别人屁股
Look at you smiIing and this person just, you know, stabbed somebody in the ass
他们就坐在隔壁桌
and now they sitting next to the tabIe next to you.
这种事经常发生
This couId be happening aII the time.
杰克！ 容我...
Jack! If I may...
嘿， 医生 我想时间也快到了
Hey, Doc, I think we're about out of time.
但我觉得好多了
But I feeI so much better.
多谢你， 你真了不起
Thank you so much. You know, you're a genius.
早安， 麦考先生
Good morning, Mr. McCaII.
我不想催你 我知道你一直很忙
I don't mean to be pushy and I know you get hit up aII the time.
我只想问一下 你是否看过我的手稿了？
I was just wondering if you had a chance to read my manuscript.
你的手稿？
Your manuscript?
马可斯牧师 我最爱的客户好吗？
Hey, Reverend Marcus. How's my favorite cIient?
我只想知道我是不是该回内布拉斯加 在老爸的农场工作
I just need to know if I'm going home to Nebraska, work on my dad's farm,
或者你可以读个20页
or, you know, maybe you couId just read 20 pages.
等我一下 我快读到你的手稿了
HoId on one second. Hey, Iook, I'm getting cIoser on your manuscript.
我把它从厨房 移到床头柜了
It's moved from my kitchen tabIe to my nightstand,
接下来会移到厕所 到时候我就会看了， 好吗？
and next, it'II be by my toiIet and that's where it'II get read, okay?
牧师， 两句话 “精彩”和“必要”， 等等
Reverend, two words, ''gripping'' and ''necessary''. HoId on one sec.
帮个忙好吗？
Hey, can you do me a favor?
帮我把轮圈擦亮好吗？
Can you poIish my rims for me?
还有别把车子停在树下 树上小鸟太多了
And don't park my car under the trees with aII those birds?
牧师， 这本《上帝， 我的钱呢？ 》 是你写过最棒的书
Reverend, Lord, Where's My Money? is the best thing you've ever written.
杰克麦考办公室， 请稍候
Jack McCaII's office, pIease hoId.
你已经在等了？ 好， 继续等， 谢谢
You're aIready hoIding? Okay, continue to hoId. Thanks.
杰克麦考办公室
Jack McCaII's office.
我不管， 带它去兽医院就好 我不知道， 妈！
I don't care. Just take him to the vet. I don't know, Mom!
我不...妈， 我要挂了
I don't... Mom, I got to go.
对， 周末非常愉快
Yes, I did have a great weekend.
对， 我要咖啡
And, yes, I wouId Iike some coffee.
我看起来很棒吧？
I Iook good, right?
我把麦片中的小棉花糖挑掉了
I finished picking out aII the mini-marshmaIIows out of your cereaI.
全挑掉了？
AII the mini-marshmaIIows?
当然除了黄色月亮以外
Except the yeIIow moons, obviousIy.
麦考先生
Mr. McCaII?
我知道我只是个助理 但我真的很感激...
I know that I'm just an assistant. And I reaIIy appreciate...
艾伦， 这是我的办公室
Hey, Aaron, this is my office.
这不是MTV台的告解室吧？
This isn't the confessionaI booth at MTV, aII right?
不是， 我知道 我从不告解的， 我只是...
No, no, I know. I know. I wouId never confess. I'm just...
我只是想说， 如果将来
I guess what I'm trying to say is that if I'm gonna
我要成为作家经纪 我不确定这样要如何...
be an agent one day, I'm not reaIIy sure how this...
你必须学我讲话 谈吐像我， 学习我！
You have to speak Iike me, taIk Iike me, study me!
学会说出想法 而且要快人快语
Learn to speak your mind, but do it quickIy.
你必须记住 这是训练的一部分
You have to remember, this is aII part of your training.
好， 很棒 我差点忘了， 周末审阅
Okay. Okay, great. I aImost forgot. The weekend read.
容我这么说
If I do say so myseIf,
我认为南极那篇投稿很棒 你看过了吗？
I thought that the Antarctica submission was pretty good. Have you read it?
当然没有， 我干嘛看？
AbsoIuteIy not. Why wouId I do that?
我解释给你听
Let me expIain something to you.
最棒的书 你只要读前五页
AII your best books have everything you need to know in the first five pages
及最后五页就知道了
and the Iast five pages, okay?
你看， 女人遇到男人
Here we go. Woman meets man.
怀孕、 战争、 孤独
Pregnant. War. AIone.
战争结束， 宝宝长大， 新男人
War over. Baby oIder. New man.
幸福快乐， 畅销书
HappiIy ever after. BestseIIer.
哇
Wow.
会议室准备好了吗？
Did you prepare the conference room?
好了， 简报弄好了 没人知道内容
Yeah. PowerPoint's aII set up, nobody knows a thing.
好， 出去吧
Okay. WeII, get out of here.
辛加
Everyone here is famiIiar with Dr. Sinja.
各位都知道辛加博士
辛加博士是当今世上
Dr. Sinja is the most popuIar
最受欢迎的非宗教教派精神领袖
nondenominationaI reIigious Ieader on the pIanet.
他是身心灵疗师 是新世纪的智慧大师
He's a hoIistic heaIer and a New Age dispenser of wisdom
拥有数千万的追随者
with a foIIowing in the tens of miIIions.
这家伙就算在平日 也能让足球场挤爆支持者
This guy can fiII up a footbaII stadium on a Tuesday.
传统的宗教领袖 总会问信徒
Our conventionaI spirit guides aIways ask the seeker,
“你要什么？ ”
"What do you want?"
我挑战传统， 请你自问
I chaIIenge you to ask yourseIf,
“生命想从我身上得到什么？ ”
"What does Iife want from me?"
“理想打算从我身上得到什么？ ”
"What does the greater purpose want from me?"
看看这家伙的粉丝出席数据
Look at this guy's attendance figures.
他的人气超过席琳狄翁、 U2
He's outseIIing CeIine Dion, U2,
葛培礼和孟汉娜！
BiIIy Graham and Hannah Montana!
他真正的哲学是什么？
What's his actuaI phiIosophy?
“静默中自有真理”之类的
''In quiet, there is truth.'' Some shit Iike that. Something Iike that.
就是典型的新世纪狗屁
Just your typicaI New Age buIIshit crap.
我的梅姑妈经常这样说 新世纪狗屁
That's what my Aunt May used to caII it. New Age buIIshit crap.
如果有人能销售新世纪狗屁 那个人非我莫属
And if anybody can seII some New Age buIIshit crap, it's me.
杰克， 这是一种精神运动
Jack, it's a spirituaI movement.
对， 每次我吃麦麸马芬 排便运动就很顺畅
Yeah, I have a spirituaI movement every time I eat a bran muffin.
-天啊！ -好吧， 杰克
-God! -AII right, aII right, Jack.
假设你能和这家伙搭上线
Assuming you can actuaIIy get an audience with the guy,
但城里不只你一名作家经纪 知道这个消息
you're not the onIy agent in town who has this information.
你为何觉得 你可以让辛加和你签约？
What makes you think you can taIk Sinja into signing with you?
我是杰克麦考， 这就是我的本事
I'm Jack McCaII. This is what I do.
嘿， 我能说服任何人 做任何事
Hey, I can taIk anybody into doing anything.
吸气
Breathe in.
吐气
And reIease.
沉淀思绪 直到无念无思
Quiet your mind untiI there are no thoughts.
你就能看到真我
Then you can see your true nature.
看到你在爸妈出生之前的真我
Your face before your parents were born.
“爸妈出生之前的真我？ ”
''Your face before your parents were born''?
真适合当儿童节目的名称
That's a great titIe for a kids' show.
真我有许多名字
It has many names.
涅盘、 见性、 极乐
Nirvana, kensho, bIiss,
神性、 空明 我们就称之为蓝色珍珠吧
divinity, iIIumination. Let's caII it the BIue PearI.
没关系， 真理有时很痛苦
It's okay. Our truth can be painfuI.
痛苦是成长的基础
Pain is the touchstone of growth.
-真适合印在T恤上 -没关系
-That'd be a badass T-shirt. -It's okay.
欢笑和哭泣是极其相似的
Laugh, cry. They're cIose cousins.
尽管释放出来
Just Iet it out.
他看到蓝色珍珠了
He sees the BIue PearI.
没事了、 没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
很多学生冥思多年
Students meditate for years
没人看过你今天看到的
and never see what you have seen today.
内在真我
Your inner seIf.
你是非常特别的人 你叫...
That makes you a very speciaI person, Mr...
麦考
McCaII.
杰克麦考， 非常感谢
Jack McCaII. Thank you so much.
抱歉， 我不知道怎么了
Sorry, I don't know what happened. I just got overcome with emotion. I'm sorry.
就是一时情绪上来， 很抱歉
我多年来专注于静思
My years and years of focused siIence
突然就让我达到...
just finaIIy deIivered me to...
-开悟？ -开悟， 对， 开悟
-EnIightenment? -EnIightenment, yes. EnIightenment.
抱歉， 拿着一下
Sorry. HoId that a second.
抱歉， 连播四次就会停了
I'm so sorry. PIay it four times and it stops.
真糟糕
That is bad.
哦， 蓝色珍珠
Oh, the BIue PearI.
蓝色珍珠好蓝哦
The BIue PearI is so bIue.
蓝色珍珠真是闪亮
The BIue PearI is so shiny
好圆润
and so pearIy.
有三样东西无法长久隐藏
''Three things wiII not Iong be hidden.
太阳、 月亮
''The sun, the moon,
“还有真理”
''and the truth.''
杰克麦考， 你今天前来有何贵干？
Is there a reason for your visit today, Jack McCaII?
先生， 我就不浪费时间了
WeII, sir, I am not one to waste time.
我知道你写了本书
I understand you've written a book.
没错
That is true. WeII, I'm an agent.
我是作家经纪
在我的职业生涯中 一直梦想要代表
And aII my career I've dreamed that I'd get to represent
一个值得我深信的人 我相信你
someone who I beIieved in. I beIieve in you.
我认为我可以帮助你 改变这个世界
And I think I can heIp you to change the worId.
我没兴趣
I'm not interested.
真的吗？
ReaIIy?
辛加博士？这个世界
Dr. Sinja? Dr. Sinja, the worId
充满迷失、 孤独的灵魂 他们需要你的智慧
is fiIIed with Iost, IoneIy souIs in need of your wisdom.
他们在那里呼唤你
And they're out there caIIing out to you
默默渴望你 我听见他们了， 我感同身受
in quiet desperation. I hear them, I feeI them.
树真是让人惊叹的东西吧？
Aren't you amazed by trees?
对， 当然！
Yeah, sure!
我最爱树了！
I Iove trees!
树， 我爱树
Trees, I Iove them. I Iove trees.
树的枝桠和叶子， 真是...
The branches and the Ieaves. It's just...
有人只想要名利
You know, some peopIe want fame and money.
但我只要大自然 给我枝桠和树就行
Just give me some nature, some branches and some trees.
我爱死了
I Iove it.
事实上我和树感觉很亲
In fact, I have such an affinity towards trees
我想我上辈子可能是一只鸟
I think I might even have been a bird in another Iife.
就是...
Just...
在树上栖息， 拥抱自然
Landing on a branch. Taking it aII in.
我想当只鸟 我想吞下你的哲理
I want to be a bird. I want to be a bird and I want to swaIIow your phiIosophy.
在我的口中反刍
And then I'm gonna spit it back into the mouths
喂养全天下的孩子
of the chiIdren of the worId.
滋养他们的灵魂， 帮你发扬光大 看着你张开翅膀
Nourish their souIs. HeIp you to grow, watch your wings spread,
帮助你展翅高飞
and heIp you to soar.
你在说什么？
What are you taIking about?
我在说要代理你的书 行销全世界
I'm taIking about presenting your book to the worId.
你读过了吗？
Have you read it?
当然读过
Of course I have.
你有什么好处？
So what's in it for you?
能帮助我的英雄拯救世界 我就心满意足了
Just the satisfaction of knowing that I heIped my hero to save the worId.
当然， 外加一成佣金
And 10%, of course.
该死！
Shit!
树划伤我了！
The tree gave me a spIinter!
不是菩提树做的 它根本没动
The Bodhi tree did nothing. It did not move.
命运都是我们自己创造的， 杰克
We aII create our own destiny, Jack.
辛加博士， 如果你交给我 我会全力以赴
Dr. Sinja, if you commit to me, I'II give you aII that I am.
身心灵合一
Mind, body and spirit. Everything.
让我成为大鸟
Let me be a big bird.
大鹰！
Hawk!
或麻雀也行
Or sparrow.
任你选， 我都配合
Pick a bird, I'm it.
你同意出版我的书？
You agree to have my book pubIished?
我求你让我发行！
I'm begging you for it!
你会依照我的意思 去传递我的哲理？
And you wiII spread my phiIosophy in the way I meant it to be spread?
这是一定的， 我向你保证， 先生
That goes without saying. You have my word, sir.
记住， 我们的话影响深远
Remember, our words have a profound
会让整个宇宙产生涟漪效应
rippIing effect on the entire universe.
一言为定
WeII, I'm counting on that.
-杰克麦考办公室 -艾伦！
-Jack McCaII's office. -Aaron!
你快去帮我买张宝座
I want you to run out and buy me a throne,
一柄权杖和一顶皇冠 因为我是国王！
and a scepter and a crown, because I am the king!
天啊， 麦考先生 你签到他了， 对不对？
Oh, my God, Mr. McCaII. You signed him, didn't you?
我当然签到他了
You bet your ass I signed him.
永远不要怀疑我！ 永远不要！
Never doubt me! Never doubt me!
这样吧
How about that? Hey, I want you to cIear my scheduIe for the rest of the day.
你把今天接下来的行程 通通取消
我要去陪陪我妈
I want to go spend some time with my mother!
让她知道她的儿子有多行！
Let her know what a big star her boy is!
好的， 陛下
Okay, done, sire.
雷蒙！ 是你吗？
Raymond! Is that you?
不是雷蒙 妈， 我是你儿子杰克
No, it's not Raymond. It's Jack, Ma. Your son, Jack.
雷蒙， 我知道你不会错过我的生日
Raymond, I knew you wouIdn't miss my birthday.
我不是雷蒙， 我是杰克， 妈
I'm not Raymond. I'm Jack, Ma.
你气色真好， 雷蒙
Oh, you Iook good, Raymond.
妈， 雷蒙是你老公
Mommy, Raymond was your husband.
他走了， 我是你儿子杰克
He Ieft. I'm your son, Jack.
我留下来了 你养大我的， 记得吗？
I stayed. You raised me. Remember?
-你好吗？ 爱蜜莉 -嘿， 杰克
-How you doing, EmiIy? -Hey, Jack.
好了， 安妮 你的客人来了
Okay, Annie, now that your guest is here,
可以吃晚餐了
we can have some dinner.
抱歉一直打给你 但她最近忘得很快
Sorry to keep caIIing you, but she's sIipping a bit more these days.
现在没有雷蒙， 她就不吃东西
Now she won't eat without Raymond.
雷蒙是你爸爸？
Raymond is your dad?
对， 他死了
Yeah, he was. He's dead now.
-我很遗憾 -我可没有
-I'm sorry. -I'm not.
你确定她可以喝鸡尾酒？
You sure she shouId be drinking these margaritas?
别担心
Don't worry.
这些鸡尾酒都不含酒精
'Cause unIike me, these margaritas are virgins.
说到这个， 米尔特！
Speaking of which, hey, MiIt!
我都能看到你裤档的蛋蛋了
I can see your cojones in that pantsuit.
好像你在皮包中 暗藏两颗大胡桃
It's Iike you're smuggIing waInuts in a poIyester purse!
好， 够了
Okay, aII right.
今晚吃墨西哥烤肉 卷饼搭配新鲜酪梨酱
Tonight it's fajitas and taquitos with fresh guacamoIe.
谢谢， 提姆
Oh, gracias, Tim.
妈妈， 你还好吗？
How you doin', Mom? You okay?
看看这套西装 你真像黑道分子
Look at that suit. You Iook Iike a gangster.
你干嘛不穿 我们结婚时那套西装？
Why don't you wear that suit we got married in?
因为我是你儿子杰克， 妈
Because I'm Jack, your son, Ma,
我因为工作， 必须穿这种衣服
and I got to wear cIothes Iike this because I need it for my work.
我是大经纪人， 记得吗？ 今天我谈成一笔大案子
I'm a big agent, remember? Hey, I made a big deaI today.
杰克？
Jack?
雷蒙 杰克一直不能原谅你的离开
Raymond, Jack never forgave you for Ieaving.
-妈！ -杰克又忘记我的生日了
-Ma! -And Jack missed my birthday again.
妈， 我是你儿子杰克， 我在这里！
Mom, I'm Jack. I'm your son. I'm here!
什么？
What?
生日快乐， 妈
Happy birthday, Mom.
卡洛琳向你问好
And CaroIine says heIIo.
雷蒙
Raymond,
是你吗？
is that you?
不， 妈， 我是你儿子杰克
No, Ma. It's me, Jack. Your son.
我必须回去工作了， 所以...
I'm going to get going now and get back to work, so...
我爱你
Love you.
嗨， 关登西欧， 你迟到了吧？
HoIa, Gaudencio. You're here Iate, huh?
嗨， 麦考先生 洒水器挂了， 但我会修好的
Hi, Mr. McCaII. The sprinkIer, it die, but I fix it.
好
Okay.
就是这个， 好美的房子， 杰克
This is it. It's a beautifuI house, Jack.
社区太棒了
The neighborhood is so sweet.
到处都是孩子
There are kids everywhere.
我在那里时
WhiIe I was there,
有辆冰淇淋车刚好开过来
an ice cream truck actuaIIy came through.
我是说， 这实在...
I mean, it's just...
太适合我们了
It's perfect for us.
但这栋房子也很完美
But this house is perfect for us.
我们在这里怀了泰勒
We made TyIer in this house.
就在这个房间里
We made TyIer in this room.
泰勒就是在这张桌子上受孕的...
We made TyIer on this tabIe. TyIer...
如果我们要继续住在这里 我希望改造一下
Okay. If we're going to stay in this house, which I'm wiIIing to do,
让家里更安全
we have to do some work to make it safer.
更有家庭气氛
More famiIy friendIy.
你在说什么？这里超安全的
What are you taIking about? This pIace is perfectIy safe.
不， 在抛光的地板后面
No. Look, just beyond these poIished concrete fIoors
是没有围篱的泳池
is a non-fenced pooI
再后面就是六百公尺深的悬崖
that backs up to a cIiff with a sheer drop of 2,000 feet.
也许我们应该等孩子长大
WeII, Iook, maybe we shouId Iet the kid grow up
看他想要怎样的生活
and teII us where he wants to Iive.
这是单身汉的住家！
It's a bacheIor pad!
他是单身汉！
He's a bacheIor! Okay. We cannot raise a famiIy in this house.
我们不能在这里 经营一个家
嘿， 我靠潜力咬牙买下这地方
Hey, Iook, I bought this house on my potentiaI
再赚钱付清， 我爱这房子
and then I earned it. I Iove this house.
我也爱 但我必须在吧台替泰勒换尿布
I Iove it, too, but I'm changing TyIer at the bar.
他睡在你的视厅室
He sIeeps in your media room.
我们好像你家的客人一样
It's Iike we're guests in your house.
该是改变的时候了
It's just time.
搬家是很大的改变
You know, moving is a huge change.
我知道， 但结婚也是
I know, but so was getting married,
生小孩也是
and having a baby.
这些改变结果都很好， 对吧？
And those turned out to be reaIIy nice changes, right?
好， 就这么办
Okay, Iet's do it.
真的吗？
ReaIIy?
重新粉刷视厅室吧
Let's paint the media room.
画些小鸭子和卡通等等
Yeah, Iet's put some ducks in there and some cartoon figures
只要保持摩登复古风格
and, you know, just keep it mid-century modern, though.
摩登复古鸭
Mid-century modern ducks. -Yeah, mid-century modern and ducks. -That's fantastic.
-对， 摩登复古和鸭子 -还真棒啊
听起来其实很酷
That actuaIIy sounds kinda hot.
杰克， 你的可恶纪录又破表了
An aII new Iow for you, Jack.
-你在做什么？ -清理啊
-Hey, now what are you doing? -I'm cIeaning up.
-那是怎么回事？ -地震？
-What the heII was that? -An earthquake?
我遇过地震， 那不是地震
I've been in an earthquake. That wasn't an earthquake.
我去看看泰勒！
I'm gonna check on TyIer!
好漂亮的树， 朋友
This is a beautifuI tree, my friend.
告诉我 你干嘛种一棵树
PIease, teII me why you wouId pIant a tree
挡在门廊正中央
right in the middIe of the patio.
我没种树啊
I no pIant the tree.
你没种树？
You no pIant the tree?
我整天都在修理洒水器
I've been here aII day fixing the sprinkIer.
我回来拿工具的
I coming back to pick up my things
砰， 树就冒出来了
and, boom, it's a tree here.
“砰， 树冒出来？ ”
''Boom, it's a tree here''?
砰
Boom.
嘿， 这是弄伤我的树
Hey, this is that tree that bit me.
他干嘛送我这样的东西
Why the heII wouId he send me something Iike this?
这是开玩笑吗？
What, is this a joke or something?
他当礼物送我
He must think it's a gift.
现在我必须留下 这该死的玩意？
WeII, now I'm stuck with this goddamned thing?
我正想送他一瓶好酒
I was gonna just send him a nice wine or, you know,
或是礼品公司的每月精选水果
a Harry and David's Fruit of the Month.
或是按摩， 或是费太太饼干
Or a massage. Or Mrs. FieIds cookies.
没错
ExactIy.
要我把它移走吗？
You want me to get rid of it?
不， 我要表现友善 留着吧， 这是我的树了
No, I gotta make nice. I'II keep it. This is my tree now.
-好， 麦考先生， 明天见 -谢谢
-Okay, Mr. McCaII. See you manana. -Thanks.
挺优雅的
Sorta cIassy.
-麦考先生？ -说快点， 艾伦
-Mr. McCaII? -Faster, Aaron.
拜托你聪明点 长话短说
PIease, be Iess dumb, but be quicker about it.
我今天头好痛
I got a spIitting headache today.
你生病了吗？
Are you sick? No, I think I'm having an aIIergic reaction or something.
不是， 可能是过敏
这会让你开心一点 这是你的皇冠
WeII, this shouId cheer you up. Here's your crown.
宝座我订好了
And the throne's on order.
但他们也有权杖 所以我买了
But they offered me a scepter, so I bought it.
你是白痴吗？
Are you a moron?
不是
No.
辛加把书送来了...
So Sinja sent his book over, and...
-很棒吧？ -你读过了？
-How great is it? -You read it?
我到底要说几遍？
How many times do we have to go through this?
我不看书的！
I don't read!
我再问一次， 辛加的书如何？
Once again, how was Sinja's book?
不， 让我告诉你 很精彩吧？
No, Iet me teII you. It was scintiIIating, huh?
你看到欲罢不能 好像收到最新一期的
You couIdn't stop reading it, just Iike it was your Iatest copy
运动画报吧？
of Juggs magazine, right?
厚度是差不多没错
It is a quick read, that's fair.
好样的， 辛加！
Way to go, Sinja!
那几乎像是为你而写的书
It's aImost Iike the book was written for you.
当然是啊！ 听好， 这本书...
Of course it was! Listen, this book is...
只有五页
Five pages Iong.
五页？
Five pages Iong?
五页
Five pages Iong.
就是一、 二、 三、 四...
As in one, two, three, four...
五， 结束
Five. The end.
不过这样想好了 这是最适合你的书
But Iook at it this way. It's the perfect book for you
因为前五页
because the first five pages
和最后五页 就是一整本书了
and the Iast five pages are the whoIe book.
艾伦， 拜托
Okay, Aaron, come on.
你是在开玩笑吧？
TeII me that you're puIIing my pecker on this one, right?
但愿我是
Oh, I wish I couId.
我没有开玩笑， 但...
I mean, not your pecker, but...
让我看看
Let me see it.
-看... -书啦！
-My... -The book!
不
No.
-这就是书？ -对
-That's the book? -That's the book.
好， 我要去他的修道场
Okay. Okay, I'm gonna go down to that ashram
把这本书塞进他屁股！
and I'm gonna ram this up his ass!
这只是题献吧？
It's just the dedication, right?
还是试读本？或作者感言？
Or the teaser? Or the thank you's.
杰克， 你还说你喜欢我的书
Jack, you said you Ioved my book.
你给我的不叫书 那是小册子
That wasn't a book you gave me, it was a pamphIet!
菜单都比那个长
I've read menus that were Ionger!
我来的路上 看到的交通标志都比那个长
I read a stop sign on the way here that was Ionger than that!
我的书是自我发掘的旅程
Now, my book is a journey of seIf-discovery.
目前这段旅程写满了五页
Now, that journey is fuIfiIIed by page five.
好， 我了解了
Okay, it's coming together now.
你袖中乾坤真不少
You know, you got a Iot of tricks up your sIeeve.
先是神奇魔树 然后是五页的书
First, the magic tree. Then the book with five pages.
接下来呢？ 你会坐上魔毯
What's next? You gonna get on a magic yoga mat
腾空飞行一圈？
and fIy around in a circIe?
然后你戛戛肚子 再吹口气
Then you rub your stomach, but then, whoosh,
精灵就会钻出我的屁股？
the genie jumps out of my ass?
保重， 杰克， 你还好吧？
BIess you, Jack. Are you okay?
我有些过敏
I'm having an aIIergic reaction.
可能是因为你送我的树
It's probabIy from that tree you sent me.
我送你树？
I sent you a tree?
看到没？
See?
原来树跑到这里来了
So this is where the tree went.
什么？
What?
真有意思
Interesting.
什么真有意思？
What's so interesting?
这些枝桠没有半片叶子
These branches don't have a singIe Ieaf.
我也注意到了
You know, I noticed that, too.
杰克？
Jack?
看着树， 然后说句话
Look at the tree and say something.
说什么？
Say what?
什么事那么好笑？
What's so funny?
真不可思议， 你不懂吗？
This is amazing. Don't you see?
感觉好像每次我开口说话
Hey, you know, it aImost seems Iike every time I say something,
就有些...
some of the...
哈？
HeIIo?
哈...
HeI...
...！
...Io!
该死！
Shit!
嘿， 你是怎么办到的？
Hey, how are you doing this?
我？什么也没做
Me? I'm doing nothing.
你和这棵树连结在一起了
You and this tree are now connected.
连结？
Connected?
看来你说话 会让你生病
It seems Iike aII your taIking is making you sick.
说话才不会让我生病
Hey, my taIking is not making me sick.
是吗？杰克 如果树的叶子全掉光会怎样呢？
Oh, reaIIy? What happens when a tree Ioses aII its Ieaves, Jack?
辛加， 你想说什么？
So what are you trying to say, Sinja?
我觉得你说得越多
It's obvious to me, the more you taIk,
叶子就掉得越多， 你的病就越重
the more Ieaves faII, the sicker you get.
病就越重？
The sicker I get?
如果叶子全部掉光光呢？
So what happens if aII the Ieaves faII off the tree?
通常这代表树就死了
That usuaIIy means the tree is dead.
嘿， 等一下
Hey, wait a second. HoId on a second.
你是说你认为
You teIIing me that you think
不管树的情况如何 我也会一样？
whatever happens to the tree happens to me?
对
Yes.
所以我可能会死！
So I couId die!
对， 但你的死亡 会是最不可思议的方式
Yes, but you wouId die in the most amazing way possibIe.
我会死？
I couId die?
也许有人会把你做成咖啡桌
Or someone couId turn you into a coffee tabIe.
辛加， 你这好笑的家伙
Hey, Sinja, you know, you're a reaI funny dude to stand here
站在这里开玩笑 我的性命都被魔树控制了！
making jokes when my Iife is being controIIed by this magic tree!
你认为树上还有多少叶子？
How many Ieaves you think are Ieft on this tree?
一千吧？
A thousand?
所以我只剩一千个字可讲？
So what do I got, a thousand words Ieft?
剩下993个字了
Now you have 993.
一字一叶
One word, one Ieaf.
我知道怎么制止这种事
WeII, I know how to make this shit stop.
不， 你不该这么做
Oh, no, no, you shouIdn't do this.
-那是谋杀！ -对， 也是蓄意的！
-That is murder! -Yeah, and it's premeditated, too!
杰克， 最好不要！
Jack, you shouIdn't do this!
辛加， 你去担心 第六页到第两百页的内容吧
You know what, Sinja? You worry about pages six through 200
让我来担心 这棵麻烦树就好！
and you Iet me worry about Mr. Tricky Tree over here!
就是这样， 我最后只想说一句！
And on that note, one Iast finaI word!
树要倒了！
Timber!
幸好你没有电锯
Be gIad you don't own a chainsaw.
为何要这样对我？
Why did you do this to me?
不是我， 我不知道是怎么回事
I didn't do this. I wouIdn't know how.
所以是宇宙诅咒我？
So, what, the universe cursed me?
也许 这是你和树之间的事
Maybe. This is between you and the tree.
等等， 如果这是真的 那我该怎么办？
Hey, wait a minute. If this is reaI, what am I supposed to do?
你听过这种事吗？ 你看过这种事吗？
You ever heard of this before? You ever seen anything Iike this?
我从没看过
I've never seen it,
但有个故事提到 有位老和尚也有这样的树
but there is a story of an oId monk that had a tree Iike this.
我一直以为只是故事
I aIways thought it was just a story.
他变得很有名望
He became very famous and honored.
所以他存活了
So he Iived. No, he died.
不， 他死了
老天
Jesus.
不， 他叫史丹
No, his name was Stan.
我今晚要去玻利维亚
I'm Ieaving for BoIivia tonight.
波托西有场灵修叫做拉帕兹
A spirituaI retreat in Potosi caIIed La Paz.
我会和那边的同事 讨论你和你的树
Let me taIk to my coIIeagues there about you and your tree.
玻利维亚？你何时回来？
BoIivia? WeII, when you coming back?
-三天 -三天？
-In three days. -Three days?
这段期间我要做什么？
What am I supposed to do untiI then?
杰克， 如果我是你 我会保持沉默
If I were you, Jack, I'd be quiet.
三天不要说话， 这不难吧？
Don't taIk for three days. How hard can it be?
喂！
HeIIo!
可恶
Shit.
少来了， 杰克
Come on, Jack.
用树诅咒你有什么目的
What is the purpose in cursing you with a tree
你每说一个字 树就会掉一片叶子？
that Ioses a Ieaf with every word you speak?
太荒谬了！
That is ridicuIous!
你说得对
I guess you're right.
太疯狂了！
It's crazy!
太荒谬了！
It's ridicuIous!
你看到了吗？
Did you see that?
看到什么？
See what?
一字一叶 杰克， 你笑死我了！
A Ieaf with every word! Jack, you sIay me!
天啊！ 我的天啊！
Oh, Lord Jesus! God, oh, God, oh, God, oh, my God!
天啊！ 天啊！ 天啊！
God, oh, God, oh, God, oh, God, oh, God!
早安
Morning.
卡洛琳-我去幼儿课， 再见 死树！
早安， 先生 今天想喝点什么？
Good morning, sir. What can I get started for you today?
多大杯？
What size?
好， 三杯特大咖啡
AII right, three venti Iattes.
你要加点面包吗？ 不要？
WouId you care for a pastry? No?
哦， 摩卡！ 三杯摩卡咖啡
Oh, mocha! Three mocha Iattes.
加量巧克力碎片马芬！ 好！
DoubIe chocoIate-chip muffin! Yum!
你要三张保罗麦卡尼CD 太好了
You want three PauI McCartney CDs. Awesome.
我超爱披头四的 他们是我的生命
You know, I Iove the BeatIes. They are my Iife.
暗杀！ 亚伯拉罕林肯！
Assassination! Abraham LincoIn!
你、 我、 枪、 开枪！
You, me, gun, shoot!
三枪
Three shots.
我今天反应有慢
I know, I'm a IittIe sIow today.
所以是三杯拿铁、 三杯摩卡
AII right, so three Iattes, three mochas,
加量巧克力碎片马芬 还有三下枪响
doubIe chocoIate-chip muffin and three shots.
没有暗杀
No assassinations.
还有三张保罗麦卡尼CD
And three PauI McCartney CDs.
总共是68.12元
That's gonna be $68.12.
可以告诉我 何时能安全过马路吗？
CouId you teII me when it's safe to cross?
你是聋子吗？我说
Are you deaf? I said,
“可以告诉我 何时能安全过马路吗？ ”
''Can you teII me when it's safe to cross?''
现在？谢了， 老兄！
It is? Thanks, feIIa!
停、 停、 停！
Stop it, stop it, stop it!
嘿， 兄弟， 怎么回事？
Hey, my brother, what's happening, brother? What's going on?
嘿！ 有人开车扫射啊？ 什么声音？
Hey! Was that a drive-by? What was that?
告诉我， 是开车扫射吗？
Somebody teII me, was that a drive-by?
谢了， 年轻人！ 白人就是有礼貌
Thanks, son! White peopIe sure is nice!
嗨， 麦考先生
Hey, Mr. McCaII.
你看过我的书了吗？
Hey, about my book, any chance you read it yet?
很棒的故事吧？
Great story, right?
你真的读了 天啊， 你不喜欢那故事
Oh, you did read it. Oh, God, and you hate the story.
好， 至少文笔不错吧？
Okay, but the writing is good, right?
不好？你干嘛不说谎骗我？
No? WeII, why don't you Iie to me?
你已经骗了我三年 说你没空看
You've been Iying to me for three years about how you couIdn't read it.
现在你突然看了， 你不喜欢
Now suddenIy you read it, you hate it,
写得很烂， 你粉碎了我的梦想
it sucks and you just smash my hopes
嘿， 韦恩， 回内布拉斯加
on the rocks of ''Hey, Wayne, go back to Nebraska
“和你爸爸一起剪羊毛”
''and shave sheep with your dad.''
你不知道当作家的滋味 我恨我自己
You don't know what it's Iike to be a writer. I hate myseIf.
我恨我自己， 你懂吗？ 我恨我自己！
I hate myseIf, do you get that? I hate myseIf!
我会帮你泊车
I'II park your car.
对， 我会帮你泊车 好个鼓励大师
Yeah, I'II park your car, Mr. Encouragement.
麦考先生， 你总算来了
Mr. McCaII, thank God you're here.
你有好多留言
I have a Iot of messages.
你要先听最新的留言 还是最紧急的？
Do you want to start with the most recent or the most urgent?
你喉咙痛？好， 别说话
You got a sore throat? Okay, don't taIk.
喝点茶如何？
Okay. How about some tea?
咳嗽药？ 笔记本？
Cough medicine? How about a notepad to write on?
好
Okay.
这样我怎么知道 你要我做什么...
WeII, then how am I supposed to know what you want me to...
麦考先生， 你不说话 是因为生我的气吗？
Mr. McCaII, are you not speaking to me because you're mad at me?
你发现我昨天提早下班了 我很抱歉
You found out that I Ieft work earIy yesterday. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
我肚子不舒服
Okay, I have stomach probIems
我必须跑回家 因为我不敢用公共厕所
and I had to run home because I can't use pubIic bathrooms.
为此我去看心理医生了
I'm seeing a therapist about it.
好
Okay.
杰克， 是关于圣诞派对吗？
Jack, is this about the Christmas party?
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry. That was the peach schnapps that tried to kiss your wife, not me.
是酒精作祟 害我企图亲你太太
我不想亲你太太
I mean, I don't want to kiss your wife,
虽然亲她的感觉像天堂
even though her Iips feIt Iike heaven.
我要走了
I'm gonna go.
天啊， 我的天
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
你找到我的摄影机 及毛皮性爱影片了
You found my video camera with the furry tapes.
打扰一下， 麦考先生
Pardon me, Mr. McCaII.
莎曼~找你
Samantha asked me to get you. She wants to introduce you to somebody.
她要介绍你和某人认识
玛丽， 他发现了
Yeah, Mary, the jig's up, okay?
他知道我们在这里做爱
He knows what we do in here,
下班后在他的办公室 在办公桌、 椅子上
in his office, after work, on his desk, in his chair.
麦考先生， 首先我想说
Mr. McCaII, I just want to say, first of aII,
是她想扮演较龌龊的动物
you know, she's the one that aIways wanted to be the fiIthier animaIs,
例如臭鼬或淘气水獭
Iike the skunk and the naughty beaver.
我试着扮演较威武的动物
I tried to be the more dignified animaIs
像野狼和加州黑熊
Iike the woIf and the CaIifornia bIack bear.
别伤害我， 我很抱歉
And don't hurt me, I'm sorry. It's just this sexuaI hunger I have. It's insatiabIe.
我只是有这种性饥渴 欲求不满
你会了解吧， 你是个...
I mean, you understand. You're a...
你想到外面 像男人一样解决此事？
You want to go outside and settIe this Iike men?
好！ 那就走吧
AII right, fine! Let's do it.
不， 我没那个意思， 抱歉
No, I didn't mean it! I'm sorry.
杰克， 我要向你介绍
Jack, I have to introduce you
克利斯坦雷杰拉图 欧洲市场部
to Christian Leger de Ia Touffe, European market.
克利斯坦， 这就是杰克
Christian, this is Le Jack.
日安， 久仰大名了
Bonjour. I've heard a Iot about you.
杰克， 告诉克利斯坦 关于辛加的事
Jack, teII Christian the whoIe story about Sinja.
把所有的细节都告诉他， 快点
TeII him aII the great detaiIs. Go ahead.
听好了， 你们会高兴死的
Ecoutez. You're going to die.
生命是一场旅程
Life is a journey.
生命是什么？
Life is a what?
生命是一场旅程？
Life is a journey?
你可以再说一次吗？
Can you repeat that, pIease?
生命是一场旅程
Life is a journey.
“生命是一场旅程”
''Life is a journey.''
生命是一场旅程， 对
Life is a journey, yeah.
我不懂
I don't get it.
你喜欢派对
You Iike to party on us.
-午安 -嗨
-Good afternoon. -Hi.
杰克麦考
Jack McCaII.
对， 杰克麦考先生 你的客人到了， 这边请
Yes, Mr. McCaII, your party is waiting for you. Right this way.
你要交给我发言？
You want me to do aII the taIking?
不， 我不行 我不知道要说什么
No, no, no, I can't, I don't know what to say.
就学你那样是吗？ 那样好吗？
Just do what you wouId do? Is that good?
等等， 好吧， 我们想些暗号
Wait, wait, wait, okay. Let's have signs,
如果我表现很好 你就拉拉耳朵， 好吗？
Iike if I'm doing weII, you puII on your ear. Okay?
然后这样是表示 我还需要做得更好， 这样也可以
And then that can mean that I need to do better. That's fine, too.
我们还以为 你要放我们鸽子了
We were starting to think you stood us up.
罗伯吉尔莫， 合并部副总
Robert GiImore, VP of Acquisitions.
这是吉尔瑞德 赛门修斯特行销部主任
This is GiI Reed, head of Marketing at Simon and Schuster.
握什么手 我们是好兄弟！
Handshake. Come on, man, we are brothers!
击个掌， 吉尔
Hit me hard and high, GiI.
碰！ 这才对嘛
Bam! That's right.
艾伦怀斯柏格 经纪人、 人类的好朋友
Aaron Wiseberger, agent, friend of mankind
我喜欢你们出版的每一本书
and a Iover of every book you guys have ever pubIished.
怎么回事， 这里是麦当劳吗？
Come on, what is this, Mickey D's?
找个人来服务吧！
Let's get some service up in here!
这家伙口干舌躁呢！
Got a man with a bad case of the dry mouth!
你怎么不坐下， 来嘛
Why don't you sit your ass down, come on.
午安， 要喝点什么？
Good afternoon, can I get you something to drink?
先喝一杯吧？
How about the distiIIery to start off with, huh?
我要伏特加， 加冰块
Vodka, rocks for me.
再来四杯水， 还有这个家伙
Four waters for the tabIe, and this fine guy right here,
他要喝热威士忌 他喉咙不舒服
is gonna have a hot toddy. His voice is shot.
你知道吗？
But you know what? That's what he gets for screaming for more Iap dances aII night!
那是因为他整晚看脱衣舞 喊到沙哑了！
你这个老疯子
You crazy bastard.
我重复， 四杯水 伏特加加冰块、 热威士忌
I have four waters, vodka rocks, hot toddy.
干得好
My man.
两位， 我们不想玩什么游戏
GentIemen, we don't want to pIay games on this one.
很好， 小孩才玩游戏
Good, games are for chiIdren.
数据会说话
The statistics speak for themseIves.
辛加博士在全世界 拥有广大的粉丝群
Dr. Sinja has a huge fan base around the worId.
我们想替他 在美国增加这个粉丝群
We want to be the company to broaden that fan base here.
我们提出很好的条件
We think we have a great offer.
先付25万订金 版税百分之十五
A $250,000 advance against 15% of the gross.
听起来不错
That sounds great.
我希望你们别玩游戏了 拿出你们真正的家伙
AII right, I'ma need y'aII to quit pIaying with me and puII out your big guns
因为现在是 “看谁最大”的时间， 两位！
because this is ''Show Me Your Dick'' time, feIIas!
嘿， 杰克 你怎么一直冒汗？
Damn, Jack, Iook at you, sweating Iike a bitch.
冷静点， 老兄， 交给我 吉尔， 过来
Just chiII out, homey. I got this. GiI, come here.
吉尔， 我需要...听好了
GiI, what I need from... Stay with me.
我需要你出更高的价钱
What I need from you is to bring that paper.
你必须提高数字
You know, you got to turn the voIume up
因为目前金额 小到我根本听不到
on that offer, homey, 'cause I can't hear it.
我是年轻人 我的耳朵很好， 却听不到
I'm a young man. My ears are good. I can't hear it.
我们不能再提高金额了 因为我们连书都没看过
We can't go higher if we haven't even seen the book yet.
听起来就像这样
That's what it sounds Iike.
连书都还没看过
Look, you can't expect us to bid higher
我们不可能出更高的价格， 对吧？
when we haven't seen the book, can you?
这太荒唐了
That's ridicuIous.
你知道自己面前的人是谁吗？
Do you know who the heII you're taIking to?
我可是艾伦怀斯柏格！ 看清楚点！
I'm Aaron Wiseberger! You better recognize, son!
我觉得你的话和风度 太过污辱人又不堪
I find both your Ianguage and demeanor insuIting and intoIerabIe.
本出版社不跟胆小的混蛋做生意 吉尔， 走吧？
Simon and Schuster doesn't do business with spineIess jerks. GiI?
不， 等等！ 请等一下
No, no, no, wait! Wait, gentIemen, wait.
很抱歉如果刚才冒犯到您
Listen, I'm sorry if I offended you back there.
这是经纪人的习惯
I was just doing my agent act.
其实我连真正的学历也没有
You know? I mean, I don't even have a reaI degree.
我上过社区大学
I went to community coIIege,
还是因为我奶奶跟院长上床 我才能进去
and that was onIy because my grandma was sIeeping with the dean.
祝你们好运， 会用得上的
Good Iuck, gentIemen. You'II need it.
爸爸们等等
Wait a minute, Dads.
这儿有个对嘴唱的人
We have a Iip syncher.
吹牛的家伙
Mouther.
爸爸， 每个人都要一起唱
Everyone needs to sing aIong, Dad.
因为泰勒会跟你学， 懂吗？
See, 'cause TyIer's taking his cues from you, okay?
他要靠你才会一起唱
He reaIIy needs you to sing aIong.
泰勒， 准备上月球了吗？
Okay, TyIer, are you ready to go to the moon?
出发！
Here we go!
他终于睡了
He's finaIIy down.
可以聊一下吗？
Can we taIk?
上课期间 因为不知道歌词而被点出来
It's kind of funny how you got singIed out in that cIass
这有点好笑吧？
for not knowing the words, right?
想想看， 杰克麦考竟然不知道歌词？
I mean, Jack McCaII not knowing the words?
太少见了
That's a rarity.
这真的很贴心， 杰克
It was reaIIy sweet, Jack.
看到你们在那个圈子里 我很高兴
It makes me very happy to see the two of you in that circIe.
你和泰勒起码有一件事 能够一起做
I think it's reaIIy important that you guys have at Ieast one thing
真的很重要， 懂吗？
that you do together, you know?
所以， 他们提议一周两次
So, they offer it twice a week.
你想要哪一天？周二或周三？
Which day wouId you prefer, Tuesday or Wednesday?
不行
Can't.
你不行
You can't.
要你一个礼拜抽空一小时
You can't take one hour out of your week
陪儿子， 竟然不行？ 我无法理解
to be with your son? I don't understand.
什么？游泳池？ 这个景观？噢
What, the pooI? The view? Wow.
我正试着跟你谈孩子的事
I am trying to taIk to you about our chiId
但你又要吵房子的事？
and you want to fight about the house again?
甜心， 你能不能起码试着 跟我谈泰勒的事？
Look, honey, couId you just try for a second to taIk to me about TyIer?
不要转移重点， 什么...
Just be here with me right now. What...
显然不行 好吧， 多谢告知
ApparentIy not. Okay, that's good to know.
抱歉！
Sorry!
抱歉？
Sorry?
我会跟儿子转告你很“抱歉”
I'II Iet your son know that you're ''sorry.''
我的人生
My Iife.
是我们的人生
It's our Iife, Jack.
我记得当我们坠入爱河时 真是场轰轰烈烈的爱情
I know that when we feII in Iove, it was a whirIwind romance
好像是我提到生小孩的事
and then it seems Iike I brought up the idea of having a baby,
然后彷芬灰怪间就怀孕了
and, Iike, overnight we were pregnant.
但有时候人生就是这样
But that's just how Iife works sometimes.
你有听过“人算不如天算”吗？
Have you ever heard the expression, ''Man pIans, God Iaughs''?
两天
Two days.
两天？ 然后呢？
Two? Two days tiII what?
然后呢？
Jack, what? To what?
甜心， 你要告诉我！
Honey, you got to taIk to me!
什么？你真像个精神病患
What? You're Iike a mentaI patient
在那里又指又发怪声的， 什么？
with the pointing and the grunting. What?
我说的话让你反感
AII of my taIking is making you sick.
很好， 这样吧？
That's great. You know what?
我不说了， 如何？ 你不想谈？
I won't taIk anymore. How about that? You don't want to taIk?
我也不想谈
I don't want to taIk, either.
欢迎使用国际电话号码簿
WeIcome to the internationaI directory.
是否需要国际代码？
Are you Iooking for a country code?
你还在吗？
Are you stiII there?
是！
Yes!
你需要哪个国家的代码？
What country wouId you Iike the code for?
玻利维亚
BoIivia.
很抱歉， 无法辨识
I'm sorry. I couIdn't make that out.
玻利维亚
BoIivia.
纳米比亚， 正确吗？
Namibia. Is that correct?
不， 蠢蛋！
No, stupid!
我们的服务人员将会为你...
Let me connect you to the next avaiIabIe...
国际号码簿你好
InternationaI directory.
国家代码， 玻利维亚
Country code, BoIivia.
城市， 波托西 公司名称， 拉帕兹
City, Potosi. Business Iisting, La Paz.
辛加！
Sinja!
是！
Yes!
喂？我是辛加博士， 请问是哪位？
HeIIo? This is Dr. Sinja. Who's caIIing?
请问是哪位？
Who's caIIing?
杰克麦考！
Jack McCaII!
杰克！ 是的 所以你想了解目前情况吗？
Jack! Yes, weII, you're caIIing for an update, yes?
抱歉， 杰克， 我忘记了 要尽量少说话， 对吧？
I'm sorry, Jack, I forgot. Trying to save our words, right?
我没说错的话 请发出动物的声音
Just make an animaI noise if I'm correct.
好的， 其实我还没有发现
Good. WeII, I have nothing yet,
但我明天就回去 我一下飞机就会立刻打给你
but I return tomorrow and I shaII caII you as soon as I Iand.
再见！
Bye, Jack!
靠！
Dickhead!
“靠”是一个字！
''Dickhead'' is one word!
你惹毛我了！
You are messing with the wrong guy!
你好， 先生 我能帮你展开全新的一天吗？
What's up, my man? Can I get something started for you today?
好的， 三倍特大拿铁
Sure. Venti tripIe-shot Iatte.
三倍特大冰拿铁
Venti tripIe-shot iced Iatte.
多加牛奶
Extra miIk?
杰克！ 昨天午餐到底怎么了？
Jack! What the heII happened at Iunch yesterday?
我接到对方的来电 他们要抽手了
I got a caII from Simon and Schuster. They're puIIing out of the deaI.
说有个愚蠢低阶的经纪人跟你一起来
They said some twerp junior agent came to the meeting with you,
那家伙既粗鲁、 低俗又笨！
that he was rude, uncouth and stupid!
我已经完美安排了蓝灯书屋
Now I have teed up Random House perfectIy here,
别搞砸， 这些人准备好付钱了
so don't screw this up, too. These guys are ready to pay.
维持一般生意的形式 这交易就成了
Just keep it down to business and it's a done deaI.
戴维斯小姐？
Miss Davis?
蓝灯书屋的派克先生在线上
I've got Mr. Parker from Random House on the Iine.
我们开始吧 这不费吹灰之力
Okay, here we go. It's a no-brainer, Jack.
聋哑人都能让它成交
A deaf mute couId cIose this deaI.
我要开会， 结束后打给我？
I'm Iate for a meeting. CaII me when you're done?
保证会打给我？
You promise you're gonna caII me?
别让我失望， 杰克
Don't Iet me down, Jack.
杰克！
Jack!
我是唐派克 这里还有莎拉艾略特、 瑞克派尼诺
Don Parker. I got Sarah EIIiot, Rick Panero with us.
你在吗？
Jack, are you there?
喂？杰克， 你在吗？
HeIIo? Jack, are you there?
喂？
HeIIo?
很好
Good.
我猜莎曼~告诉过你 我们很感兴趣
Hey, I guess Samantha toId you we were interested.
太好了
Great.
那我们来谈这笔交易吧？
So what do you say we make a deaI?
杰克？
Jack?
喂？要不要开始？
HeIIo? You want to get started or no?
好， 听着
Good. Okay, Iisten.
我们省掉客套话 直接讲重点吧
Let's skip the formaIities, get right down to specifics.
内部谈过了
We taIked internaIIy.
我们觉得较实际的金额为25万
We thought a reaIistic offer wouId be 250.
如何？
What do you say?
提高到27万5千呢？
What if I bumped it up to 275?
你该好好考虑一下27万5千
You reaIIy need to consider the 275.
要不要讨论一下？
Why don't you run it by your peopIe?
我们等你
We'II wait.
好的， 好的
Okay, okay, okay.
抱歉， 抱歉
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
借一下， 晚点解释
I just need to borrow this for a minute. I'II expIain Iater.
借一下， 杰克要用
I need to borrow this. It's for Jack.
瑞秋， 不给我这该死的娃娃
RacheI, I think there's some reaI secret shit
我就要告诉其他人 你不可告人的秘密了！
that I'm gonna start teIIing everybody if you don't give me the damn doII!
27万5千的开价如何？
So what's the verdict on the 275?
要不要接受？
Are you in, are you out?
我们连书都还没看到
We haven't even seen the book.
有什么问题吗？ 不相信我们的宣传部门吗？
What's the probIem? You don't trust our pubIicity department?
确实好到没话说！ 那还迟疑什么？
You're damn right they are! So what's the hang up?
你怎么开始骂人了？
Hey, you gonna start throwing insuIts?
听好， 如果你要这样处理的话
Listen, if that's the way you're gonna handIe this,
我们就取消吧 留意你的态度
we'II just caII the whoIe deaI off. Check the attitude.
好吧， 杰克 透露些讯息吧
AII right, Jack, Iook. Just throw me a bone here.
提高到30万如何？
What if I bumped it up to 300?
好吧！ 我放弃！ 50万！
Fine! I give up! Five hundred!
50万若核准
If I get 500 approved,
就能敲定了吗？
are we cIosed?
你这下欠我大人情了， 先生
You are gonna owe me so big next time, mister.
泰勒在长牙齿 可怜的家伙， 这很可怕
TyIer is teething, poor thing, and it's terribIe, you know,
因为他不睡的话， 我也不能睡
because he's not sIeeping, I'm not sIeeping.
杰克没甜头吃吗？
Jack's not getting any ass?
你能不能...
Can you...
他连厨房的婴儿防护都不做
He won't even baby-proof the kitchen.
我何必要给他？
Why in the worId wouId I give him some?
你穿着阿妈内裤吗？
Are you wearing granny panties right now?
什么？
Excuse me?
你穿着阿妈内裤吗？
Are you wearing granny panties right now?
还有哺乳胸罩？
And a nursing bra?
不告诉你
I am not answering that.
不用说我也知道
You don't have to.
我已经尽力了
I am doing the best I can.
我有礼物要给你
I have a present for you.
什么东西？
What is that?
不要因为袋子里的东西 而改变对我的印象
Do not judge me by what's in this bag.
不行
No.
不行， 我没办法
No, I cannot do this.
有何不可？
Why not?
因为我不是那种女生
Because I am not that kind of girI.
所以才发明了龙舌兰酒
That's why they make tequiIa.
龙舌兰酒加翘臀 等于幸福美满
TequiIa pIus ass equaIs happiness.
我能帮你吗？
How can I heIp you, sir?
要见人
Meeting someone.
我听说你很准时的
I was toId you'd be punctuaI.
哇！ 你可真是个小家伙啊？ 不过无所谓
My! You're a wee sIip of a thing, aren't you? But aII right.
上船吧
CIimb aboard.
很抱歉搞错了
I'm so sorry about the mix-up.
卡洛琳麦考在413号房
CaroIine McCaII's in room 413.
在找人吗？
You Iooking for someone?
我想了你一整天
I've been thinking about you aII day,
还有一堆我要对你
about aII the things I want to do
做的事情
to you.
我来帮你
Let me heIp you.
告诉我
Now why don't you
你想要什么
teII me what you want.
告诉我
TeII me aII the IittIe
你希望我对你做 什么样的坏事吧
naughty things you want me to do to you.
哼哼哈兮
Bow-chik-a-bow-wow.
别害怕， 宝贝 我只是让气氛更刺激点
Don't be scared, babe. Just spicing things up a bit.
规则如下
Here's how it's gonna work, baby.
你说得越多 我就做得越多
The more you say, the more I do.
告诉我你想要什么， 说吧
So teII me what you want. Come on.
说些色色的话吧， 杰克
TaIk dirty to me, Jack.
你不要我吗？
Don't you want me?
对吧？
Yeah?
那就说出来
Come on, then say it.
告诉我 你要我做什么
TeII me what you want me to do.
对， 说些色色的话
Yeah, yeah, taIk dirty.
说吧， 杰克
Come on, Jack.
你做得到的， 没错
Come on, you can do it, that's right.
就是这样， 说吧
That's right, Jack, come on.
说出来， 杰克
Come on, Jack, Jack.
说色色的话， 杰克！
TaIk dirty to me, Jack!
真不知道我在想什么
I don't know what I was thinking.
甜心 我只是想要向你证实
Honey, I just wanted to try to prove to you
我们可以有些乐趣
that we couId stiII have fun.
但看来是没办法
But I guess we can't.
我真的感到好羞耻
So, I'm so embarrassed.
好吧， 这样行不通
Okay, Jack, this isn't working.
我们不再... 我们不再像过去那样了
We don't... We're not what we used to be.
自从泰勒出生以后
I mean, not since TyIer was born.
一切都变了
It's just different.
好像我们忘记 如何跟彼此沟通了
It's Iike we've forgotten how to taIk to each other.
你不觉得变了吗？
I mean, don't you think it's different?
我连你爱不爱我都不知道了
Jack, I don't even know if you Iove me anymore.
你还爱我吗？
Are you stiII in Iove with me?
好吧， 那要说出来
Okay, weII, then, you have to say that,
你必须告诉我， 好吗？
you have to teII me that, okay?
我要听你说
I want to hear you say it.
我爱你
I Iove you.
不， 杰克 拜托， 我要清楚听到， 好吗？
No, Jack, pIease, I need to hear it. Okay?
我要你说： 卡洛琳 我爱你， 我要和你在一起
I need you to say, ''CaroIine, I Iove you, and I want to be with you.
“我这辈子的余生 都要和你一起， 绝不放你走”
''I want to spend the rest of my Iife with you and never Iet you go.''
拜托你这样说好吗？
Can you pIease say that?
你能说吗？
Can you say that?
能！
Yes!
就这样
But that's it.
好吧
Okay.
好吧， 我们或许 需要见个专业的婚姻咨询
Okay, so I think that we shouId see a professionaI,
我们可以一起见面对谈的人
somebody that we can sit down and taIk to,
他或许能帮我们想办法 把这一切都结束掉
and they can heIp us figure out how to end aII this.
干嘛？
What?
有棵树
There's a tree.
掉叶子、 力量
Losing Ieaves. Strength.
我说话， 叶子掉
When I taIk, Ieaves go.
叶子掉
And when Ieaves go,
我死
I die.
是这么一回事？
That's what this is about?
某种中年危机胡扯？
Some midIife crisis buIIshit?
你告诉我 什么掉叶子的烂诗
You're here to teII me this poem about your Ieaves faIIing,
像是如果跟我沟通的话
Iike if you somehow communicate with me,
你就不像男人了？
you're gonna be Iess of a man?
杰克， 出去
Jack, get out.
不， 我说真的
No, reaIIy.
出去
Go.
我想要独处， 拜托
I want to be aIone, pIease.
杰克， 出去
Jack, now.
杰克！ 莎曼~现在 正在跟蓝灯书屋的人吃午餐
Jack! Hey, Sam is at Iunch right now
讨论敲定你的生意 还有不要杀我
cIosing your deaI with Random House and don't kiII me,
但是我离开位子时
but I stepped away from my desk
有人送了一份辛加的书要给他们
and somebody sent a copy of Sinja's book over.
你在生气吗？
Are you mad?
看是谁来了！
Oh, Iook who it is!
-杰克 -嗨， 杰克
-Hey, Jack. -Hi, Jack.
今天是便服日吗？
What is this, casuaI Fridays?
好， 我们要收尾了
Okay, Iook, we got to Iock this up,
让他们感兴趣 然后在改变心意前快签约
get them excited and signing before they change their minds.
有把书带来吗？
Did you bring the book?
没关系， 玛丽会送一份来 坐下吧
It's okay. Mary's bringing a copy Iater. Sit, sit, sit, sit, sit.
你若吸到这种东西 碰， 会让你飘飘欲仙！
You breathe that stuff in and, boom, it make you Ioco!
这下到齐了
Now we're aII here.
我来说一下进度
AII right, Iet me catch you up to speed.
我们刚讲到行销和推出的策略
We're taIking about marketing and roIIout strategies.
行销和推出策略
Marketing and roIIout strategies.
我们要以全球性的思维来想
I think we shouId aII be thinking gIobaIIy.
碰！
Boom!
你还好吗？
Are you okay, Jack?
杰克？
Jack?
你要水吗？好吧
Can I get you some water? AII right.
先生， 需要吃点什么吗？
Sir, may I bring you something to eat?
要不要从沙拉开始
Maybe you'd Iike to start with a IoveIy saIad.
给他水就好， 谢谢
He'II just have water, thank you.
谢谢
Thank you very much.
对， 这些东西让我们都有些晕头转向了
Yes, it's getting us aII quite giddy, the whoIe idea of it.
所以若是电视的部分
So, I think, as far as teIevision goes,
我们要全面的媒体曝光
we want a fuII-scaIe media bIitz.
晨间秀、 深夜秀 所有的谈话性节目
Morning shows, Iate night, aII the taIk shows.
像这样的书
With a book Iike this,
我们可以针对折扣店 连锁俱乐部、 咖啡店
we can target discount stores, cIub chains, coffee shops.
我还想到 可以尝试产品搭配广告
I aIso think we shouId Iook at product tie-ins.
像是辛加的饮食或运动影片
Like Sinja's diets or workout tapes.
好主意
Good idea.
我准备好合约了 就在资料的背面
I've prepared contracts, which you'II find at the back of your packets.
你会发现价钱有点提高
You'II notice that the price has gone up sIightIy
这是为了反映 作者对此专案的行销贡献
and that's to refIect the author's marketing commitments to this project.
不， 谢了， 杰克 我现在是低糖饮食
No, thank you, Jack. I'm on Atkins.
我们应该现在就直接
But I reaIIy don't see any reason why we shouIdn't go ahead
签下合约
and sign this right now
这样我们就能团结一致 以专业的团队继续进行
so we can aII move forward together as one professionaI team.
杰克！
Jack!
我其实用电子邮件寄就行了
Yeah, I couId have just emaiIed this to you.
书只有五页
The book is just five pages.
你说什么？
I'm sorry, what?
艾拉， 这一定是误会
Ira, I'm sure this is aII some sort of misunderstanding.
-莎曼~ -保持联络
-Samantha. -We'II be in touch.
杰克！ 你到底怎么回事？
Jack! What the heII is wrong with you?
像个酒醉的三岁小孩一样？
Acting Iike a drunk 3-year-oId at the tabIe?
没有告诉我 辛加的书只有五页？
Not teIIing me that Sinja's book is five pages Iong?
这件事你没有任何话可说吗？
Don't you have anything at aII to say about this?
杰克， 你被开除了
Jack, you're fired.
好， 好， 请冷静下来
Okay, okay, pIease caIm down.
你要放轻松， 麦考先生
I need you to reIax, Mr. McCaII.
因为我是来帮你找回工作的
'Cause I'm here to heIp you get your job back.
我们做得到的
I am and we're gonna do it.
但现在， 我真的很担心
But right now, I'm just reaIIy concerned
你额头上的血管会爆开
about that vein in your neck expIoding.
我这次一定会理解的 我保证， 开始吧
I'm going to get it this time, I promise. I promise. Here we go.
好的， 你
Okay, you.
对， 那个是你
Yes, that's you.
你...
You...
在说话...你说话？
You're taIking... You taIk?
好， 这部分搞懂了 然后在下雪
Okay, we've estabIished that. And it's snowing.
不对？好的， 好的， 是
No? Okay. Okay, yeah.
显然不是下雪
ObviousIy not snowing.
叶子
The Ieaves.
叶子掉... 叶子从树上掉下来
The Ieaves faII... The Ieaves faII off the tree.
好， 好
Okay. Okay.
你说话时 叶子从树上掉下来
When you taIk, aII the Ieaves faII off the tree.
这真好玩 不好玩， 我不是那个意思
Okay, this is fun. It's not fun. I didn't mean it Iike that.
当树上所有的叶子都掉光
And when aII the Ieaves faII off the tree,
你睡觉
you are asIeep.
好， 不是睡觉
Okay. You're not asIeep.
你犯法， 你是停车标志？
You're iIIegaI. You're a stop sign?
好的， 抱歉， 抱歉
Okay, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
你模仿明星舞？
You're vogueing?
你...
You...
叶子掉光， 你会死！
When aII the Ieaves faII off, you die!
我懂了
Oh, Iisten, I get it.
我真的懂 我大学时服过迷幻药
I get it. I once took acid in coIIege
那时我以为我的头发也有心跳
and I thought for sure that my hair had a heartbeat.
其实没有！
But it didn't!
好吧
Okay.
饼
Pancake.
这是巧合
It's a coincidence.
才不是巧合， 笨蛋！
It's not a coincidence, you idiot!
你看， 掉更多叶子了！
Look, you just Iost five more!
很抱歉， 我可以坦白说吗？
I'm sorry. Can I be reaIIy honest here?
我大概理解你为何被开除了
I think I know why Samantha fired you.
因为这太疯狂了 不可能有这种事情
'Cause this is very crazy. This is Iike Britney territory.
说得好， 麦考先生 但我要走了
Okay, weII said, Mr. McCaII, but I'm gonna go.
不， 没事 我们没事了
No, it's cooI, we're cooI. We're cooI.
留在这？ 你要我看着叶子？
Stay? You want me to keep an eye on the Ieaves?
好吧
Okay.
没想到我竟会怀念挑棉花糖
Never thought I'd miss the marshmaIIows.
等等， 你要去哪？
Wait, where are you going?
祈祷？
To pray?
当天使？
To be an angeI?
好吧， 祝你好运！
Okay, got it. Good Iuck!
饼
Pancake.
现在呢？
How about now?
说话时就掉叶子
FaIIing as we speak.
你好
HeIIo.
谢谢， 愿神保佑你
Thank you. God bIess you.
天啊， 叶子都掉光了
Oh, my God, aII the Ieaves just feII off.
什么？
What?
我开玩笑的
No, I'm kidding.
愿神保佑你
God bIess you.
哈利路亚， 现在呢？
HaIIeIujah. Now what?
没用
Nope.
毛毛！ 快下来！
Mittens! Mittens, come down!
下来， 毛毛
Come down, Mittens.
还掉？
FaIIing?
没错
Yeah, they are.
还有， 莎曼~打来要我回去
And, Jack, Samantha's office caIIed. They want me back.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
杰克， 吃晚餐了！
Jackie, dinner time!
来， 我的小宝贝
Here you go, sweetie pie.
-你瞧！ -我就知道是火腿
-VoiIa! -I knew it was gonna be ham
还有马铃薯泥
and mashed potatoes!
妈， 我可以先拿自己的吗？
Mom, may I pick my piece first?
当然可以 因为你这么有礼貌地请求
You may, because you asked so poIiteIy.
谢谢
Thank you.
好棒
There you go.
用摇的， 不要摔破， 杰克！
Shake it, don't break it, Jackie!
还记得“我爱火腿”的舞吗？ 跳给我看
Hey, remember the ''I Love Ham'' dance? Do that dance.
杰克
Jackie.
杰克， 是我 不对， 我就是你！
Jackie, it's me. I mean, I'm you!
杰克， 我们都在！ 是我们两个！ 杰克， 我在这！
Hey, Jackie, we're here! I'm us! Jackie, I'm here!
不， 爸， 你不在
No, Dad, you're not here.
你从来都不在， 你离开了
You were never here. You Ieft.
我才不是爸
I'm not Dad.
派， 好棒的料理
Pie. What a concept.
玻利维亚的派 根本无法跟美国的比
You can't get pie in BoIivia, not Iike pie in America.
水果派， 奶油派...
Fruit pies, cream pies...
抱歉
Sorry.
真是惊人
It's quite amazing
一个人能说这么多 不经大脑的话
how many thoughtIess words one can speak.
你不觉得吗？
Don't you think?
你气色很差， 杰克
You don't Iook weII, Jack.
你的婚姻毁了？
Your marriage is over?
她带着孩子离开了
She took the baby and Ieft.
工作也毁了？
Your job, too?
很遗憾， 杰克
Sorry, Jack.
我只能给你我的信念， 还有...
AII I have for you are my beIiefs, and, weII,
机场买的雪花玻璃球
this snow gIobe from the airport.
快解开我跟这该死的树的关系！
You unhook me from this goddamned tree!
-别这样 -我要死了！
-PIease, Jack. -I'm dying!
我知道你很害怕
I know you're scared.
我也跟你说过 我会带着答案回来
And I know I toId you I'd come back with the answer.
但答案就是
WeII, the answer is
根本没有答案
there is no answer.
没人知道树的事情
No one knows about this tree, Jack,
我真的努力试过了， 好吗？
and beIieve me, I tried. Okay?
我不知道你到底该怎么办才行
I don't know how this is going to work out for you,
但我知道的是 你需要找到平静
but what I do know is that you need to find peace.
如果你当我是个骗子 你为什么会来找我？
If you think I'm a charIatan, then why are you here?
要听我的建议吗？
You want my advice?
你需要找到自己心中的真理
You need to find the truth about yourseIf.
这满简单的 你需要安静下来
It's quite simpIe, Jack. You need to get quiet.
不只是嘴巴上 还有心灵上
Not just with your mouth, with your mind.
在这片宁静中 你会聆听到真理
And in that quiet, you wiII hear the truth.
你的人生里 还有其他还没解决的事情吗？
Do you have any other unresoIved reIationships in your Iife?
很好
Good.
你的太太呢？ 她知道你爱她吗？
Then your wife, does she know that you Iove her?
我一直这样告诉她！
I teII her that aII the time!
话语呢？杰克， 要更多话语
Words? More words, Jack.
你告诉她的 就像毫无意义掉下来的叶子那样吗？
You teII her, Iike meaningIess Ieaves that fIy off a dying tree?
话语
Words.
你无法让她感受你对她的爱吗？
Can't you show her that you Iove her?
平静下来 告诉他们， 你有多爱他们
Make peace. Show them that you Iove them.
而且要真诚
And be truthfuI.
你需要接受
You need to accept the possibiIity
当所有的叶子从那棵树 掉光的时候...
that when aII the Ieaves faII off that tree...
麦考先生？
Mr. McCaII?
嘿！ 我一直打给你 传邮件给你
Hey! I've been caIIing and emaiIing,
我想到能够保住你工作的绝妙点子
and I got great ideas about how to save your job.
辛加的书能成功
Sinja's book can work.
对， 我也很兴奋
I know, I'm excited, too.
我们都想错了
We've been thinking about it aII wrong.
麦考先生， 你有在听吗？
Mr. McCaII, are you Iistening?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
你把自己怎么了？
What'd you do to yourseIf?
你的酒臭味跟我爸一样
You smeII Iike my dad.
需要帮忙吗？ 不用？好吧
You need some heIp? No? Okay.
我不觉得喝醉 是目前最棒的反击计划
I'm not sure that getting drunk is the best pIan of attack right now.
你
You.
都是你的错！
It's aII your fauIt!
是喔， 那这样如何！
Oh, yeah, how do you Iike that?
干杯！
Cheers!
该死的杂草！
Freaking weed!
麦考先生， 别说了， 来吧
Mr. McCaII, stop taIking. Come on.
肥料只是大便！
You know, fertiIizer is crap!
所以你吃的其实是大便！
That means that technicaIIy, you eat shit!
别说话了， 白痴！
Stop taIking, you idiot!
快停止！
Just stop!
这就对了
That's it.
什么？
What?
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我要结束掉 我要用放克乐结束一切！
I'm ending it. And I'm ending it funky!
好吧
Yeah, okay.
这节奏真棒
It's a hot beat. That's the shit. That's HaroId MeIvin and the BIue Notes.
就是这个 哈洛梅尔文与蓝调乐团
由泰迪潘德盖斯主唱！ 唱吧， 泰迪！
Featuring Teddy Pendergrass! Sing that shit, Teddy!
杰克， 别说话了
Jack, stop taIking.
你在做什么？
Jack, what are you doing?
别让女人跑了
Done Iost your woman.
-我女人跑了 -闭嘴！
-I Iost my woman. -Jack, shut up!
知道这代表什么吗？ 什么也不是！
You know what that means now? Not a goddamned thing!
你在做什么？别说话
Jack, what are you doing? Stop taIking.
有什么关系？ 你看看我的家人
What does it matter? Look at my famiIy. Look at my peopIe.
-杰克！ -看我的家人！ 多漂亮
-Jack! -Look at my peopIe! It's beautifuI.
我的家庭， 很漂亮吧？
This is beautifuI, my famiIy, huh?
你在自杀！ 快停止！
You're kiIIing yourseIf! Stop!
-为什么？ -快停！
-You know why? -Stop!
杰克！
Jack!
闭嘴！
Shut up!
别说话了！
Stop taIking!
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
卡洛琳
CaroIine.
你在大学里学到的东西 真的不够你应付
There's reaIIy nothing in coIIege that prepares you
真实世界
to work in the reaI worId.
树， 你听得到吗？
Tree, can you hear me?
树
Tree.
我们都快死了， 树
We're dying, tree.
请告诉我该怎么做
PIease, teII me what to do.
是我
It's me.
我是杰克麦考
My name is Jack McCaII.
如果你能听见我
If you can hear me,
你听到的不是我在说话的声音
what you're Iistening to is not the sound of my voice.
而是我内心的声音 我脑海里的想法
It's the sound of my inner voice, the one inside my head.
麦考先生？
Mr. McCaII?
喂？
HeIIo?
听得到吗？ 我是疗养院的爱蜜莉
Can you hear me? It's EmiIy from the nursing home.
今天是你母亲的生日 她认为雷蒙会来
It's your mom's birthday and she expects Raymond to be here.
麦考先生？
Mr. McCaII?
听着
Look.
我知道你要什么
I know what you want,
但我觉得我们之间没什么好谈了 好吗？
but I just don't think that there's anything more to taIk about, okay?
因为你不肯...
Because you won't...
你
You.
我
Me.
我们
We.
永恒
Eternity.
给我的吗？
Is this for me?
这是披头四的唱片
It's a BeatIes record.
这是《白色专辑》
It's the White AIbum.
而且是原始初版！
It's an originaI first press!
这真的要送给我吗？
Is this reaIIy for me to keep?
对
Yes.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢谢
去开他的车
Go get his car.
你真的读了？
You actuaIIy read it?
棒
BriIIiant.
棒？真的吗？
BriIIiant? ReaIIy?
哇
Wow.
卖
SoId.
卖？
SoId?
卖出？这是一万元耶！
SoId? That's $10,000!
一万元耶！ 我爱你
That's $10,000! I Iove you, man.
谢谢
Thank you.
对
Yeah.
我立刻就帮你处理， 麦考先生
I'm gonna take care of that for you right away, Mr. McCaII.
还会顺便加油
I'II gas it, too.
这是谁负责的？
Who's responsibIe for this?
你一定会爱上它， 我保证
You are going to Iove that, I guarantee it.
尝尝看
Yeah? Take a taste.
我要搭云霄飞车
I want to ride the roIIer coaster.
我要搭摩天轮
I want to ride the Ferris wheeI.
我要搭云霄飞车
I want to ride the roIIer coaster. I want to ride the Ferris wheeI.
我要搭摩天轮
-RoIIer coaster. -Ferris wheeI.
-云霄飞车 -摩天轮
天气真好， 但风很大， 该走了吧？
It's sunny, but it's windy. ShouId we go?
你可以穿我的毛衣
You can wear my sweater.
所以你才会在外套下面 穿一件毛衣吗？
Is that why you wore a sweater under your jacket?
你早就知道我会这么说
You knew I wouId say that.
过了42年， 你还是想跟我在海滩独处
After 42 years, you're stiII trying to get me aIone on the beach.
或许吧
Maybe. Maybe.
雷蒙， 是你吗？
Raymond, is that you?
是
Yes.
雷蒙， 你终于来了
Raymond, you finaIIy came.
坐下！
Sit!
告诉我， 告诉我 你都做了些什么？
TeII me, teII me, what you been doing?
今天是我生日
It's my birthday.
要吃生日蛋糕吗？
You want some birthday cake?
什么？
What?
不能说话， 喉咙痛
You can't taIk. Your throat.
那就休息吧， 雷蒙 我有好多话要跟你说
Rest then, Raymond. I have so much to teII you.
喜欢我的房间吗？
Do you Iike my room?
真的好棒
It's so nice.
我的东西全在这里
I've got aII my things here.
但有时候
But sometimes,
我会孤单
I get IoneIy.
雷蒙， 我会变得好...
Raymond, I get so...
但是我总是可以仰赖杰克 他都会来看我
But then, I can aIways count on Jack. Jack aIways comes.
他会带花给我 帮我的忙， 当我们出去散步时
And he brings me fIowers, heIps me, and when we go for waIks,
所有的女士都羡慕我 因为他帅极了
aII the Iadies are jeaIous because he's so handsome.
我真以他为荣， 雷蒙
I'm just so proud of him, Raymond.
看吧， 你错过看杰克 成长为大男人的机会了
See, you missed Jack grow into the greatest man.
他真的好厉害 他什么都会做
I mean, he's amazing. He can do anything.
杰克是我活下去的唯一原因
I mean, Jack's my onIy reason to Iive.
但他总是这么愤怒
But he's so angry.
对你愤怒， 对自己愤怒
Mad at you, mad at himseIf.
我想他认为是因为自己的关系 你才会离开的
Now, I think he beIieves you Ieft because of him.
那时他只是个孩子 但是每天都怀着那种愤怒
He was just a kid, but he carries that anger every day.
我真希望他能放下
I wish he'd Iet it go.
如果全都放下的话 他一定会开心多了
He'd be much happier if he'd Iet it aII go.
雷蒙
Raymond,
你要告诉杰克
you need to teII Jack
自己有多爱他
how much you Iove him.
我们是家人
We're famiIy.
人生
Life's
少了家庭就不值得活下去了
not worth Iiving without famiIy.
对吧？
Right?
没有人要唱歌庆祝吗？
Isn't someone going to sing to me?
我喜欢蛋糕 杰克， 你也是吧？
I Iike cake, don't you, Jack?
再见， 妈， 我爱你
Bye, Ma. I Iove you.
麦考之墓
嗨， 爸
Hi, Dad.
-杰克？ -对
-Jack? -Yeah.
我不是爸， 我是你
I'm not Dad. I'm you.
-我也是杰克 -才不是
-I'm Jack, too, you know. -Are not.
-是 -不是
-Am, too! -Are not.
我好想你， 爸 你到哪去了？
I missed you, Dad. Where have you been?
你离开了， 虽然我有看到你几次
You Ieft and then I saw you a few times,
但是已经隔很久了
but then it was a Iong time.
然后你死了
And then you died.
我真的很抱歉， 杰克
I'm so sorry, Jack.
我想你不会知道 最后一次见到某人
I guess you never know if the Iast time you see someone
会不会是自己这辈子 最后一次见到他
is going to be the Iast time you ever see someone.
我真希望有补偿你的办法
I wish there was a way I couId make it up to you.
有啊
There is.
-怎么做？ -来追我啊！
-How? -Chase me. Come on!
雷蒙杰克麦考之墓
我原谅你
I forgive you.
杰克？杰克？
Jack? Jack?
你一定不相信！
You're not going to beIieve this!
杰克， 那棵树又恢复生机了 真不可思议！ 你可以说话了
Jack, the tree, it came back to Iife and it's incredibIe! You can taIk.
千字遗言
You've written a beautifuI book, Jack. I'm so proud of you.
你写了一本很动人的书 我以你为荣
你又抱我了， 杰克 我应该跟你说过了
You're hugging me again, Jack. We spoke about this.
这是我活着的理由！ 这是真的我！ 死去的是假的我
That's why I'm aIive! This is the reaI me! That was a fake me that died.
我真的好爱你， 再来一次
I just Iove you so much. Come here.
-嗨！ -嗨
-HeIIo! -HeIIo.
朋友们
Friends.
向你致敬
Namaste.
欢迎到我的办公室
WeIcome to my office,
是我内在的外部表现
the outer manifestation of my inner being.
你们都在我心中
You're both inside me.
多么动人的书， 多美妙的礼物
What a beautifuI book. What a gift
可以拿着、 阅读、 销售
to hoId, to read, to seII.
-艾伦 -是
-Hey, Aaron. -Yes.
别哼歌
No chanting.
当然了， 请见谅， 智者们
Of course. Forgive me, wise ones.
好了， 我们这里有三个提案 三个大提案
AII right, we got three offers here, three big offers.
嘿！
Hey!
每一个都不错
Any of these three wouId be fine.
不， 不用急 筹码都在我们手上
No, no, no, ain't no need to rush, homey, we got aII the Ieverage here.
好， 现在我们有个机会
AII right, what we have is an opportunity
让这三家互相较劲
to pit aII three of these suckas against each other
然后完全掌握他们
and just grind 'em into the dirt.
反正就是榨干他们身上的每一分钱 然后...
Just take 'em for every Iast penny they got, you know, and...
当然 全然都是精神上进行的
In an entireIy spirituaI way, of course.
艾伦， 你现在是大牌经纪人了
You know what, Aaron? You're the big agent now.
门上写的是你的名字 你来挑吧？
You got your name on the door. Why don't you pick, huh?
想要吃派吗？
May I interest you in a sIice of pie?
我很想， 但我现在 需要去另一个重要的地方
I'd Iove to, but I reaIIy have somepIace important I need to be right now.
什么？ 比派还重要？
What? More important than pie?
没错， 但再来个拥抱吧
ActuaIIy, yes. But give me another hug.
我爱你！
I Iove you!
没错， 我是大牌经纪人 门上写的是我的名字
That's right. I'm the big agent now. That's my name on the door.
史帝芬！
Steven!
我的亚洲风味果仁里 怎么有个芥末豆？
Why is there a wasabi pea in my Asian traiI mix?
真抱歉， 怀斯柏格先生 我以为都挑出来了
I am so sorry, Mr. Wiseberger. I thought I got them aII.
这里就有一个
WeII, here's one.
有你的快递
There's a deIivery for you.
快拿来啊
WeII, bring it in.
糟了
Oh, shit.
抓好， 我来帮你打开
HoId stiII, Iet me get this open for you.
你知道我不爱惊喜
Jack, I don't Iike surprises. You know I don't.
你会爱上这个
You're gonna Iike this one.
你知道上次的惊喜怎么了...
You know what happened the Iast time I tried to do a surprise...
-你会喜欢 -什么？
-You're gonna Iike this one. -What is going on?
-把小孩放下 -好
-I'm putting the baby down. -Okay.
好， 好了
Okay, aII right, okay.
-可以拿下来了吗？ -好， 我帮你解开
-Can we pIease take it off? -Okay, now, I'II take the bIindfoId off.
-拜托快解开 -解开， 好
-Yes, pIease, take it off. -Take it off. Okay.
杰克， 这是我一直要你来看的房子
Jack, this is the house I've been trying to get you to come see.
你一定要看里面
You have to see the inside.
我已经看过了
I've aIready seen the inside.
什么意思...为什么？
What do you... Why?
你打算出价吗？
Are you thinking about making an offer?
噢， 不行
Oh, no, I can't.
-为什么？ -这已经是我的了
-Why not? -I aIready own it.
哇
Wow.
这一步相当正确
This is a step in the right direction.
没错
Yes.
但不能只做这件事， 杰克
But you can't just do this one thing, Jack,
就以为接下来一切都会顺利
and think that everything is gonna be hunky-dory.
-事情不是这样的 -我听懂了
-That's not how it works. -I hear you.
你在听？
You do?
听到了吗？
You hear that?
什么？
What?
寂静
The siIence.
很安静
It's quiet.
我喜欢
I Iike it.
你到底是谁？
Who are you?
宝贝， 树
Honey, the tree.
-是怎么... -对
-How did... -Oh, yeah.
我叫关登西欧小心挖起来 然后就...
I had Gaudencio carefuIIy dig it up and next thing you know...
砰， 树就冒出来了
Boom, it's a tree there.
-碰 -碰
-Boom. -Boom.
碰、 碰、 碰
Boom, boom, boom.
-他说“碰”吗？ -对
-Did he say, ''Boom''? -Yes.
-碰 -噢， 赞！
-Boom. -Oh, shoot!
Mandarin Traditional